Register of the Jay Lovestone papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- PRINTED SUBJECT FILE, 1904-1989 (Boxes 755-898)
  - World politics
    - United States government publications, 1945-1975 (Folder 893: 5)
    - Great Britain Foreign and Commonwealth Office publications, 1978-1986 (Folder 893: 6)
    - Foreign Affairs Research Institute publications, 1976-1982 (Folder 893: 7)
    - Bulletin of the International Commission of Jurists, 1964-1967 (Folder 893: 8)
    - South, 1982 (Folder 893: 9)
    - The World Today, 1956-1970 (Box-folder 894: 1)
    - Bullitt, William C., The Great Globe Itself: A Preface to World Affairs, photocopy, 1946 (Folder 894: 2)
    - Fleming, D. F., The Cold War and Its Origins, Vol. I, 1917-1950, extensive typed excerpts, 1961 (Folder 894: 3)
    - Serial issues, 1951-1986 (Folder 894: 4-5)
    - Serial issues, 1951-1986 (Box-folder 895: 1-2)
    - Journal articles, 1960-1988 (Folder 895: 3)
    - Clippings, 1945-1988 (Folder 895: 4)
    - Pamphlets and booklets, 1949-1977 (Box-folder 896: 1-2)
    - Miscellany, 1954-1986 (Folder 896: 3)
  - Yemen, 1978-1981 (Folder 896: 4)
  - Yugoslavia
    - Yugoslav press translations transcribed by the United States Foreign Broadcast Information Service, 1952-1982 (Folder 896: 5)
    - Yugoslav publications
      - Socialist Thought and Practice
        - 1984-1985 (Folder 896: 6)
        - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 897: 1)
      - Serial issues, 1953-1962 (Folder 897: 2)
      - Pamphlets, 1946-1967 (Folder 897: 3)
    - General, circa 1943-1987 (Folder 897: 4)
    - Dissidents and human rights
      - General, 1966-1988 (Folder 897: 5)
        Includes considerable material by and about Mihajlo Mihajlov.
      - Committee to Aid Democratic Dissidents in Yugoslavia. Bulletin, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 898: 1)
    - Labor
      - Savez Sindikata Jugoslavije (Confederation of Trade Unions of Yugoslavia) publications
        - Yugoslav Trade Unions, 1957-1986 (Folder 898: 2)
        - Pamphlets and miscellany, 1948-1969 (Folder 898: 3-4)
          Includes Salaj, Djuro, Les syndicats yougoslaves dans la lutte pour le socialisme, 1951; The Truth about Yugoslav Trade Unions, 1952; Yugoslav Trade Unions under New Conditions, 1959; Deleon, A., The Yugoslav Worker: Who Is He? What Does He Think? What Does He Aspire to?, 1962; Romac, P. and J. Franic, Workers' Self-Management in Factories, 1962; and The Living Standard and Social Position of the Worker, 1964.
      - Miscellany, 1950-1970 (Folder 898: 5)
        Includes Tito, Josip Broz, Workers Manage Factories in Yugoslavia, 1950; Topalovich, Zivko, Les usines aux ouvriers: l'expérience yougoslave, 1952; and Vukmanovic, Svetozar, Problems of Unity in the International Trade Union Movement, 1966.
  - Zimbabwe, 1969-1982 (Folder 898: 6)
- MEMORABILIA, undated (Box 899)
  Convention badges and miscellany.
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1927-1939, 1953-1972 (Box 900)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfield records determiend by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2015 November release of records, 1927-1939, 1953-1972 (Box-folder 900: 1-2)
    1927-1939: Includes meeting minutes, statements, correspondence, financial documents, and speeches related to the Communist Party, U.S.A./Communist Party (Opposition), particularly the split between them resulting from differences related to the Communist International.
    1953-1972: Includes memoranda, reports, correspondence, and summaries related to international labor movements and communism in the United States.
  - 2017 release of records, 1948-1970